# **Shahin Nazarov**

Around 4+ years of software engineering experience working with **financial**, **betting**, **cryptographic**, and **e-commerce** services companies involving extensive interaction and engagement with software design, documenting, testing, development as a **Senior Software Engineer**. Currently seeking **Software Engineering**, **Software Development**, and **Solution Architect** positions and would be keen to learn and get comfortable with new tools and technologies if the position requires.



#### **EXPERIENCES**

## **Caspian Tech CJSC**, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- Designing a new scaleable **betting system**
- Making the standards for configurations, coding style, testing and documentation
- Applying zero-downtime deployment with Kubernetes technologies
- Making CD/CI infrastructure with versioning for all applications
- Creating and developing new applications both microservice and SOA based
- Implementing 3rd party odd providers (e.g. sportradar)
- Optimizing the betting system for passing provider's certification requirements
- Developing risk management system with real-time data analyzing

## **PaySis LLC**, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

JUNE 2018 - MAY 2019

- Making the **payment system** support multiple payment processors(e-comm)
- Implementing new integrations with aggregators and vendors
- Integrating with new payment processing systems (e.g. MasterPass)
- Optimizing the speed of the system using caching technologies
- Automating daily tasks for reporting
- Developing new projects and REST APIs for (mobile) clients

# B.EST Solution LLC, Azerbaijan — Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

- Extending the open-source X-Road project by implementing new features
- Automating SOAP-based web services (generating STUB files and autodetecting new web services)
- Integrating e-signing services with Europe (OASIS DSS)
- Developing a management portal for signing/verifying
- Implementing CD/CI infrastructure and containerization all applications
- Optimizing the current system with implementing EDD patterns

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION:

**Address**: 5 Cavadkhan street, Nasimi region, Baku, Azerbaijan

Nationality: Azerbaijani Birthday: 1997/04/01 Phone: +994708900999

Email:

me@shahinnazarov.com

**Skype**: shaheen.nazarov **LinkedIn**:shaheen-nazarov

Website:

<u>shahinnazarov.com</u> **GitHub**: <u>nazarov-pro</u>

Twitter: <a>@shaheennnazarov</a>

#### **CERTIFICATION**

**CKAD**: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (Expires: 02/2023).

**IELTS**: (Expires: 01/2021).

### **LANGUAGES**

Azerbaijani (Native)

**English** (Professional)

# CCI Technologies LLC, Azerbaijan — Software Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Developing new features for the ERP system
- Writing documentation for REST and SOAP web services
- Making UML diagrams(class, flow, use case, sequence)
- Applying new REST APIs in the client-side(web)
- Analysing & optimizing SQL scripts
- Resolving bugs in website and backend with the feedback of the client

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Azerbaijan State University of Oil and Industry,** Azerbaijan — *Master*

Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) Engineering

**SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2019** 

# **Azerbaijan State University of Oil and Industry,** Azerbaijan — *Bachelor*

Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2017

#### **SKILLS**

Programming languages: Java (expert), Golang (proficient), C# (prior

experience), JavaScript (prior experience)

Software architectural design: Monolithic, Microservices, SOA, EDD, TDD

**SQL/ORM Frameworks**: JPA, Hibernate, MyBatis, JOOQ

Spring Technologies: Spring Core, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring MVC, Spring

Data, Spring Security

Web Services: REST, SOAP, Grpc

Databases (RDBMS/NoSQL): OracleDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Version Control Systems: Git

DevOps Tools: Jenkins, TeamCity, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux Schell Scripting,

Nexus, ELK Stack, Graylog, Prometheus (with Grafana)

Other: Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ (with AMQP and MQTT protocols), Maven,

Gradle, Redis, Memcached, Cryptography